foreign
quarter performance the company saw
growth in net uh earned premium but
still was below expectations their
fourth quarter loss rate loss ratio is
also expanded although their
profitability is above what was being
expected by uh the street gopal
balachandran is Chief Financial Officer
and chief risk officer at Dyson salon by
General Insurance he's joining us right
now to take some questions gopal good to
have you with us here good morning
thanks for your time uh some specific
straight off the bat gopal what kind of
Trends did you see in the motor
third-party book if you can start there
and why was why is the loss ratio there
gone up
so good morning Prashant and good
morning everyone uh so on motor third
party I think specifically uh as we keep
saying uh you have to always look at the
portfolio lost experience over longer
Horizons because this particular segment
exhibits very long tail of claims
development running into several years
so hence in a particular quarter you
will always find aberrations between in
terms of the Lost experience a better
outcome is to kind of look at the loss
ratio numbers more on an year-on-year
basis which if you would have seen let's
say for the year gone by for motor third
party the loss ratio was about 72
percent uh in fact this number is
slightly lower than what we had seen for
the last year which was about 74 uh
quarter as I said obviously there are
multiple factors that goes into it and
ends to that extent one should look at
and year and year comparison
all right hi good morning gopal thanks
so much for joining in well I'm looking
at your numbers and I say Lombard you
all sold a large motor pool of close to
around 280 crores or to appear in
February 2023 right now what would have
been the combined ratio if you didn't
sell this
so that again good morning Nigel uh so
to my mind as we are trying to put out
it's more a one-off transactions that we
have done and what we are explaining
also in English call yesterday it does
not have any kind of a material impact
insofar as the combined ratio is
concerned having said that the
transaction is definitely a commercially
viable one but in terms of the impact on
the combined issue it does not have a
material impact even if you would not
have done that particularly okay all
right but you have been guiding that the
combined ratio will come in lower I
think uh you're guiding for around 102
percent odd how do you achieve this uh
you know going ahead what kind of
rationalization steps will be you'd be
looking at
yeah so absolutely so again when you
look at maybe if you were to step back
uh maybe a year and a half back at which
point of time maybe the combined ratios
when we kind of did the integration with
bharti access to the limited 105 on a
blended basis even at that point of time
we had said possibly for fy23 we will
look at getting to a combined which is
around 104 which is what we have been
able to achieve and even at one year
back we had kind of spoken about by fi25
possibly to get the command issues down
to 102 percent uh so there are multiple
limits that we kind of work with uh
clearly in terms of increase in uh
increase in pricing is one of the levers
that we kind of largely uh look at for
example on the retail Health this
February we have kind of affected a
price increase of about 19 on the
renewable part of the health segment uh
so therefore pricing is definitely one
of the levers that we have we equally
look at actively focusing a lot on claim
services efficiency because that
typically forms the bulk of the combined
ratio breakdown if you were to look at
it and third and more importantly we
will continue to make our investments in
very various areas of expanded
distribution but early signs of success
of those Investments translating into
incremental revenues is already
something that we are seeing so hence
efficiency and operations will also be
the third level that one will look at
okay so you are saying a combined ratio
of 102 is what you hold on to by fy25
got that can you tell us for fy24
particularly what are you looking at in
terms of a premium growth as well as on
profitability what are the numbers that
you're targeting
so again that's a great question Sonia
because uh
step favor to kind of look at this
market now for the year gone by even for
the year gone by the industry cloth
about 16.4 percent and for ICC Lombard
we had a shared about the market at
about 17 but even if you look at longer
Horizons over the last 15 years the
market has compounded at 15 and given
the opportunities as one is seeing even
in terms of the robot forward uh
particularly when you look at let's say
fi 24 or Beyond we believe the market
should continue to grow in the range of
15 to 20 and from an ICS alone but
standpoint we would obviously want to
see a similar kind of maybe beating the
market uh by maybe one or two basis
points over the market growth rates from
a revenue perspective on the combined
ratio as we have kind of spoken about I
think the current combined exit was
closer to 104 directionally we would
obviously want to see a declining Trend
in Combined even for fy24 and as we're
heading to fi20 if I get to that number
of 120.
uh I got that gopal uh could you uh
confirm if so there has been this
ongoing GST investigation uh with
regards to general insurers
uh could you confirm if I say Loma has
also received a notice
so I think in so far as the tax matter
is concerned I think we are as you
rightly said across the industry uh
multiple players in the markets
obviously has been kind of uh called for
informations and documentation and even
from Isis and Lombard standpoint we have
been submitting and extending the
necessary cooperation that is required
in so far as the tax authorities are
concerned and hence we will obviously
wait and see how things kind of further
shape about that is it a is it a uh it's
a tax demand uh gopal
at this point of time we have not
necessarily received any particular
demand notice as I said this is more
currently at the stage of uh seeking
information and documentation and in
line with what let's say other players
in the market are also kind of
exhibiting we are also extending
necessary cooperation in terms of making
this information available to the tax
authorities
all right uh gopal you know what's the
outlook for crop insurance for fy24
let's post the acquisition of bharti AXA
will it be around four to five percent
of your total businesses give us some
outlook on that particle
yeah I think uh so again Nigel uh uh the
what we have been kind of talking to the
market on the crop side is obviously we
would want to continue to stay invested
in that segment but having said that you
are right if you look at the overall mix
of crop tour aggregate revenues has been
at a single digit number and even as we
kind of head into fy24 the process is
obviously to kind of see that number
staying around that levels of between
four to five percent of the overall
revenues that's the thought that we have
on the website okay I also wanted to
know what is the progress as far as the
banker Channel partners are concerned
access bank HDFC Bank what kind of
market share have you gained and what
does the way forward look like
so that's a great question Sonia because
uh at the time when we kind of announced
the bharti AXA transaction obviously one
of the things that we amongst other
things that we were able to get as a
part of the deal was access to a couple
of large private Banks as you rightly
mentioned both access as well as HTC
bank and clearly at that point of time
when we announced the deal the market
possibly had an appreciation as to these
distributions will subsist with us uh in
terms of the long-term Prospect we are
extremely happy to note that we have
been able to kind of subsist that even
as we speak and clearly what we have
been also able to do is to increase the
wallet share which in the past used to
be a single digit number in terms of
contribution because bhartiyaksa had got
access to both access and HDFC very
recently and therefore they are a single
digit wallet share in terms of both
those distribution Partners today over a
two figure cycle we have actually been
able to get into a double digit uh
market share in both of those
distribution Partners so very very
excited with the way how things is
playing out particularly with respect to
close the bank partners that we were
able to get an access to
um this is something we've discussed
earlier earlier as well but now with the
new expenses of management guidelines
could you tell us what is the uh you
know what's the thinking how much can
you get the eom number down by each year
I think you were at
29.6 percent in f523
so one if you ask me directionally again
this change in the expense of management
guideline is an extremely positive
development because uh as you rightly
mentioned this particular regulation
kind of looks at uh the transaction more
at a company level and the regulator has
put out a threshold at 30 in terms of
what you can have as experience of
management from an isosceles standpoint
consistently not just the year gone by
but even otherwise we have always
operated within that threshold of 30 and
hence to that extent uh we are kind of
quite comfortably placed uh when you
look at the market participants which is
public information uh many players in
the market are actually operating at a
threshold which is more than 30. and
there in fact the regulator has given a
Glide path to bring down their expensive
management to less than 30 percent which
we believe from an isosceles standpoint
actually an opportunity for us to
possibly look at uh maybe increasing
Market presence gopal this won't affect
Business Development uh in individual
segments as I mean you know to kind of
operate the way you want to
so in fact in fact the change in the
regulation is exactly that because
earlier we were actually having further
sub limits in terms of individual lines
of businesses in terms of what you could
expand as expense of management but the
change in the regulation exactly is done
away with sub lines or sublimits in
terms of individual lines of businesses
and give the desired flexibility which
the industry has been seeking and the
regulatory has rightfully responded to
make sure that they will monitor the
overall expense of management at a
company level now it's for the
individual companies to decide how do
they want to kind of use that experience
of management threshold in terms of the
various segments of businesses that they
want want to kind of underwrite our
source
okay uh you know another question that I
am sure a lot of investors have is
whether you would want to at some point
Enter The Life Insurance segment as well
which would complement your current
health portfolio any plans of doing that
so at this point of time we have not
thought about that Sonia while I know
that there has been a lot of
conversations that has been happening in
the context of a composite license uh
supported to answer your point at this
point of time you have not thought about
that but honestly I think you will wait
for some of these developments to happen
and maybe take a call at an appropriate
time
you know we have uh sort of a large
conglomerates uh thinking thinking and
talking about entering the space jio is
one ah right and the number of players
generally also is set to go up over the
over the next couple of years I mean we
have the data from applications to irda
to start a insurance business not just
general but life as well
uh so competitive intensity will go up
so when you earlier you said I mean
you've got three levers one is pricing
the first one we mentioned was pricing
how much of that is is that going to be
a lever going forward in in what is
going to be a highly competitive
scenario according to you briefly
that's a great question so if you look
at so when you look at our combined
ratios Prashant we are as I said
operating at a combined of 104 but if
you look at the market the market is
operating at a combined of 118 116 218
so clearly I think in so far as the
stress that is getting exhibited on
players in the market and their ability
to continue to remain competitive
obviously will be put to a question as
we kind of look forward plus the fact
mentioned that many players in the
market are already operating at an
expense of management greater than 30
and there again they will have to look
at bringing down that threshold to less
than 30. that again by itself presents
an opportunity to your point on
competition this Market has always seen
being seen a lot of entrance kind of
playing out and the current regulatory
theme being to significantly Drive
penetration is where maybe there is a
significant interest on competition as
well uh over the last several years we
have
seen players enter
and therefore that's definitely
definitely welcome step the question is
we will have to see which product line
which geography does each of this new
entrants are kind of actively looking at
if it is with respect to a particular
geography or a particular product line
then therefore to that extent at a at a
company level or maybe at an industry
level across lines we may not see so
much of competition but if it's an
entrant who wants to look at a
multi-line multi-presence then we will
have to wait and see how this space
place
you know you've given us the guideline
in terms of combined ratio coming down
to around 102 and as you said it's much
lower than what uh currently as well
much lower than what the industry
average is what about loss ratio can you
give us an outlook for fy24
so Nigel it's a combined issue because
there are various moving in Parts in
terms of the Lost experience as well as
the expense ratios which are typically
the components of the combined and there
could be different segments that will
exhibit maybe a higher loss ratios and
lower expenses equally there are
segments which operate with maybe lower
loss relation higher cost of
distribution so the way we would
obviously want to transition is a mix of
both so hence to that extent we would
not be able to specifically put out a
number on the loss ratio having said
that historically if you were to see our
loss ratios have kind of tended towards
a band between 70 to 75 percent
okay all right that was a very extensive
discussion thanks a lot gopal for
joining in uh that's ICICI Lombard with
the business and the way forward let's
slip into a quick break on the other
side of the break very quiet Market not
too much happening but mitesh Tucker
will be joining in to give us some
technical trades don't go anywhere stay
tuned for that
[Music]